<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sustainable Business | 王若宇</title>
    <link>/zh/tags/sustainable-business/</link>
      <atom:link href="/zh/tags/sustainable-business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Sustainable Business</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><copyright>2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Sustainable Business</title>
      <link>/zh/tags/sustainable-business/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Product Line Recommendation for Dove</title>
      <link>/zh/post/dove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/zh/post/dove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove should launch a new set of eco-friendly body care products to the market. The price premium will eventually cover the costs of organic and recycled certification and new product design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better fit in the intensively competitive market, follow the sustainability trends, and enhance Dove’s reputation in corporate social responsibility, I recommend Dove to introduce a new eco-friendly product series in body care and baby care. Commodities will adopt organic oat milk as one of the main ingredients with recycled paper packaging in milk carton shape. Customers may be willing to pay more for innovative and environmental friendly goods. Still, it will require time and money to earn necessary certificates and modify normal boxes into shower-friendly containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of Unilever, Dove, a personal care brand, established in 1957 only with a beauty bar (&amp;ldquo;Dove&amp;rdquo;). Now Dove expands as an international brand, owning factories in 21 countries, with products sold to over 80 countries (Bhasin &amp;amp; Nesselrode 2018). Dove’s marketing channels are diverse: retail stores, discount stores, supermarkets, and online (Bhasin &amp;amp; Dexter 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004, Dove initiated Real Beauty campaigns involving building confidence and self-esteem for women, which went viral at that time (&amp;ldquo;Dove&amp;rdquo;). Target customers of Dove are middle or middle-upper-class people. Most of them are women between 15-50 years old who care about their appearance and would like to spend money on healthier products with less harmful chemicals (Bhasin &amp;amp; Nesselrode 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers today have a high tendency for sustainable and organic products. According to the statistics report from SimilarWeb, 85.05% of people get to dove.com by searching with the leading keyword “Organic” in 2019 (&amp;ldquo;dove.com Traffic Statistics&amp;rdquo; 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to Unilever’s pledge on less plastic, Dove plans to use zero plastic on beauty bars globally before 2020, switch all plastic packaging into 100% recycled ones before 2025, and have created a new technology to reduce plastic in deodorant (&amp;ldquo;Dove moves to 100% recycled plastic bottles&amp;rdquo; 2019). Dove also obtained the accreditation from People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA), presenting their products are cruelty-free without any experiment on animals (&amp;ldquo;Dove Goes Cruelty-Free&amp;rdquo; 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’Oréal, one of Unilever’s competitors, started a sustainable personal care brand Seed Phytonutrients in 2017. The brand featured in botanical ingredients and paper-based packaging (L’Oréal Group). Compared to similar brands, Seed captured a considerable price premium. For example, an 8.5 fluid ounce shampoo can be sold at $24 in Seed, but at $7.99 in L’Oreal Paris on their websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a.Market segment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.Vegans;
ii. Green advocates;
iii. Parents who carefully choose products for their children;
iv. Young people who like to try novel and well-designed products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b. Willingness to pay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most customers of Dove are not price-sensitive, meaning that they would pay for the price premium in exchange for organic and eco-friendly products. Dove fans, recognizing Dove’s impact on changing social perception, may support the new campaign about the environment as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Vegan people who enjoy the oat milk may also be interested in these products. Plus, the cruelty-free products can show their value and concept as nature protectors. Environmental enthusiasts may find paper packaging performing better in creating less plastic waste than recycled plastic bottles. The organic food level experience will bring another winning point. Combining with baby care products, oat milk offers parents an impression of moisture and mild nourishment. The organic certificate seems healthier and more trustworthy than Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson who are often under suspicion with hormone issues in their baby products (CBS News 2012). The unique food-like design of the products will also catch people’s eyes on them immediately. They may imagine when applying the products, their bodies will feel like drinking oat milk too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove needs certifications from non-government organizations to convince consumers that its green products are guaranteed. One of the famous NGOs, The Forest Stewardship Council (FSC), is most familiar and trusted by Customers. To secure the FSC recycled label, Dove must verify all wood in the products come from 100% reused material (&amp;ldquo;FSC Labels&amp;rdquo;). In the production process, every section is under a strict custody chain from certificate Conformity Assessments Bodies (CABs) (&amp;ldquo;Assurance Services International&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) certificates organic body care products as the same rigid regulation as organic food. Products with less than 70% organic ingredients cannot use the term “organic” (&amp;ldquo;Cosmetics&amp;rdquo; 2008). Dove also has to pay less than $750 to USDA for the organic certification cost-share program (&amp;ldquo;Organic Certification Cost Share Programs&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, it is not sufficient to take the milk cartons as body care packaging — the new generation of pack demands robust and anti-water technologies and designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up, huge costs will lie in organic raw materials, schemes for recycled containers, and all honest, responsible production resulting from these certifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommendation&#34;&gt;Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove can also approach popular brands for organic oat milk like Oatly. The cooperation between two different areas will draw much attention and increase profits. When customers choose a body wash, they may discover the organic product associated with their familiar food brands. Other consumers might fall in love with the smell after trying the wash and become potential customers for oat milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove.” Unilever USA, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unileverusa.com/brands/personal-care/dove.html&#34;&gt;https://www.unileverusa.com/brands/personal-care/dove.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhasin, Hitesh, and Graham Nesselrode. “Marketing Strategy of Dove - Dove Marketing Strategy.” Marketing91, 16 June 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-strategy-of-dove/&#34;&gt;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-strategy-of-dove/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhasin, Hitesh, and Dexter. “Marketing Mix of Dove - Dove Marketing Mix and 4 Ps.” Marketing91, 20 May 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-mix-dove/&#34;&gt;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-mix-dove/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove.com Traffic Statistics.” SimilarWeb, 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.similarweb.com/website/dove.com#search&#34;&gt;https://www.similarweb.com/website/dove.com#search&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove Moves to 100% Recycled Plastic Bottles.” Unilever Global Company Website, Oct. 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unilever.com/news/news-and-features/Feature-article/2019/dove-moves-to-100-per-cent-recycled-plastic-bottles.html&#34;&gt;https://www.unilever.com/news/news-and-features/Feature-article/2019/dove-moves-to-100-per-cent-recycled-plastic-bottles.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove Goes Cruelty-Free.” PETA, 9 Oct. 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.peta.org/about-peta/victories/dove-goes-cruelty-free/&#34;&gt;https://www.peta.org/about-peta/victories/dove-goes-cruelty-free/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’Oréal Group. “Seed Phytonutrients - L&#39;Oréal Group: World Leader in Beauty: Official Website.” L&#39;Oréal - L&#39;Oréal Group, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.loreal.com/brand/professional-products-division/seed-phytonutrients&#34;&gt;https://www.loreal.com/brand/professional-products-division/seed-phytonutrients&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBS News. “Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson to Phase out Potentially Harmful Chemicals by 2015.” CBS News, CBS Interactive, 15 Aug. 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/johnson-johnson-to-phase-out-potentially-harmful-chemicals-by-2015/&#34;&gt;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/johnson-johnson-to-phase-out-potentially-harmful-chemicals-by-2015/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“FSC Labels: Forest Stewardship Council.” FSC Labels | Forest Stewardship Council, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fsc.org/en/page/fsc-labels&#34;&gt;https://fsc.org/en/page/fsc-labels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Assurance Services International.” ASI, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asi-assurance.org/s/find-a-cab&#34;&gt;http://www.asi-assurance.org/s/find-a-cab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Organic Certification Cost Share Programs.” Organic Certification Cost Share Programs | Agricultural Marketing Service, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ams.usda.gov/services/grants/occsp&#34;&gt;https://www.ams.usda.gov/services/grants/occsp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmetics, Body Care Products, and Personal Care Product. Apr. 2008, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/OrganicCosmeticsFactSheet.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/OrganicCosmeticsFactSheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
