<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruoyu Wang</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ruoyu Wang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Ruoyu Wang</title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Overhaul of Toxic Substances Control Act – “A Perfect Storm”</title>
      <link>/post/tsca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tsca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 40 years of waiting, the antiquated and ineffective Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) finally embraced the most sweeping overhaul in 2016. The official name of this amendment is Frank R. Lautenberg Chemical Safety for the 21st Century Act, in memory of the senator who dedicated to reforming until his death (Richard Denison, 2016a). This Act passed smoothly with 403:12 in the House and unanimous voice consent in the Senate (Environmental Defense Fund, 2020; Final Vote Results for Roll Call 238, 2016). Surprisingly, this environmental bill could gain mutual support in the polarized bipartisan Congress. What happened during the process might provide valuable experience for future legislation. However, after analysis and summary of the whole process and incentives underneath, I believe that this bipartisan breakthrough was the consequence of the combination of many positive factors, in other words, “a perfect storm”. Possible affecting elements were the conversion of stakeholders, replacement of key players in the Congress, the movable position of the initial law, and the underlying bipartisan networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industries shifted their position&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the most critical stakeholders, the light industry’s position somewhat determined the speed and direction of the reform wind. American Chemistry Council, the lead lobbying organization of chemical industries, was actively involved in the legislative process (Sheppard, 2015). Initially, manufacturers were content with the inefficient regulations. But, they started to feel the pressure from both international and domestic markets. On the outside, Europe launched stricter toxic substance rules in 2016. Both existing and new chemicals have to go through the Registration, Evaluation, Authorisation, and Restriction of Chemicals (REACH) process. As one of the main chemical product markets, the regulations directly impacted American factories (Vogel &amp;amp; Roberts, 2011). Within home country, liberal states like California and Massachusetts had already controlled toxic chemicals through over 70 state-wide laws (Vogel &amp;amp; Roberts, 2011). Products made in the US could no longer enter specific markets unless they followed the regulations. These demands led many manufacturers with no choice but to adopt formulas proven to be safe or obey the test requirements. Companies had to struggle with different standards. But if they refuse to adapt to regional regulations, they would lose market share. Therefore, they had to invest in several streamlines to fit in different markets. The extra costs could undermine those manufacturers’ competitive advantage compared to others only trade in the loose-controlled areas. Ultimately, industries were tired of wrangling with diverging rules. They looked forward to uniform federal standards (Eilperin &amp;amp; Fears, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From partisan to bipartisan reform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank R. Lautenberg was a Democratic Senator from New Jersey. Lautenberg stood with his party more than 95% votes in his lifetime (Frank Lautenberg, 2013). GovTrack also evaluated him as a far-left Democratic leader (Frank Lautenberg, former Senator for New Jersey, 2013). He devoted his last career period to pursuing a safer environment with less toxic chemicals (Cory Gerlach, 2016). However, it took more than 20 years to accomplish his long-cherished will (Richard Denison, 2016b). Lautenberg’s first attempt -The Kids Safe Chemicals Act yielded in 2005- won the support from Democrats and environmental non-government organizations while strongly objected among Republicans and light industrialists without a doubt (Richard Denison, 2016b). But on the good side, this premature bill spurred attention and discussion associated with the unfavorable 1976 chemical law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Sen. Lautenberg and Reps. Henry Waxman (D-Calif.) and Rep. Bobby Rush (D-Ill.) introduced separate amendment proposals on the Toxic Substances Control Act (Environmental Protection, 2010; Richard Denison, 2016b). Both bills granted EPA more authority to supervise the toxic chemical substances. Nevertheless, lousy timing pulled these bills to nowhere: they were introduced when the Congress tried to cut EPA’s budget. Besides, it was near the midterm election, legislators, especially Republicans, did not want to waste time on these environmental measures (Vogel &amp;amp; Roberts, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of being frustrated by the past failure, Lautenberg turned to Sen. David Vitter (R-LA.) and developed a bipartisan bill in 2013. The partnership seemed unrealistic. David Vitter is a conservative Republican who put financial, taxation, or immigration issues above environmental protection (David Vitter, former Senator for Louisiana, 2020). Lautenberg represented environmentalists, and consumers kept pursuing safety for the household, while Vitter is the firmest ally of the chemical industry (Plautz, 2013). Opponents argued the compromised bill might defer the interests of the chemical companies rather than consumers (Sheppard, 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key players in the Congress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate Committee on Environmental and Public Works and House Energy and Commerce Committee are the two key panels conducting and engaging environmental affairs. Back in 2013-2015, when Lautenberg and Vitter first introduced the bipartisan reformation, Sen. Barbara Boxer (D-Calif.) was the chairwoman of the Senate environmental panel. Disappointed with the mild overhaul, she vocally against the federal preemption clause in the first version (Eilperin &amp;amp; Fears, 2016). Environment-passionate states, like California, had tightened their toxic chemical regulations (Anthony Adragna, 2016). The preemption of state autonomy would undermine their mature and safe monitoring system. Her position and the untimely death of Lautenberg halted the reform efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Sen. Lautenberg passed away, Sen. Tom Udall (D-N.M.) carried on with his work on the bill and continued to polish it (Kimberly Dean, 2015). At the same time, Republicans regained the majority position in the Senate in 2015, 114th Congress. Sen. Jim Inhofe (R-Okla.) replaced Boxer as the chairman in the Environmental and Public Works Committee. Republicans started to seek support for this bill, even from Democrats. For example, Inhofe endorsed the “Climate change is real and not a hoax” proposal from Senator Sheldon Whitehouse (D-R.I.), though Inhofe personally does not believe in man-made global warming (Dina Cappiello, 2015). In exchange, the environmental panel, including Whitehouse and two other liberal Democratic senators, voted in favor of the legislation. The bill was able to continue to the next step (Anthony Adragna, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more Democratic senators joined the team with the bill. Sen. Richard Durbin (D-Ill.) and Sen. Ed Markey (D-Mass.), who was the ally of Boxer, now became the 59th and 60th cosponsor (Udall, Markey, Durbin Announce Agreement on Chemical Safety Reform Bill, 2015). Under the dual stress, Boxer agreed to vote for the act, but she would constantly negotiate and amend it afterward. Boxer’s back-off brought more feasibility to the measure. Her attitude change was crucial because many Republicans might give up this bill if it would take more time to argue and consider. Without bipartisan support, the toxic substances amendments would end up nowhere as Lautenberg’s past acts (Anthony Adragna, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side, Rep. Frank Pallone, Jr. (D-N.J.) stepped up as the top Democrat on the House environmental panel during the 114th Congress. Pallone and Energy and Commerce Committee Chairman Fred Upton (R-Mich.) determined to build the reform bill with a narrower scope but still consider the most sensitive needs. In this way, they could avoid long-lasting debates and conflicts and reach an agreement quickly (Anthony Adragna, 2016). At last, the House passed the narrower reform plan by a 398-1 vote (Environmental Defense Fund, 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After months’ concessions and reconciliation, the bicameral negotiation fruited as a new law. Though the bill offered no one everything they wanted, the compromise version already made substantial improvement over the status quo (i.e., TSCA 1976) (Richard Denison, 2016a).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideology spectrum assumptions for the bill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Representative John Shimkus (R-Ill), most of the proposals died during the compromise and never found a happy medium for both of the Parties. The Lautenberg Act was just a rare and lucky one (Anthony Adragna, 2016). Therefore, we could assume that the TSCA was notably on the right. Because industries desired a nation-wide regulation with more certainty, the outdated law no longer fitted in their interests. Republicans, allies of the chemical industry, moved their stances to the left side of TSCA. While Democrats always stood on the left side, opposed the inadequate and weak Act, and sought liberal amendments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we put the reform bills at the orange dashed lines, we might acquire situations that could satisfy both Democrats and Republicans. Hence, we could calculate the compromised area that reform could finalize eventually. Any other areas would receive strongly objective and blow off the whole bill. But the exact position of the final version would depend on the majority in the Congress and influence of other stakeholders. As far as Republicans and chemistry companies, they would like to nudge this bill a little from the status quo but not hurt their core benefits. The Lautenberg Amendment is most likely in the area between the Republican and the status quo. For minority Democrats and environmental groups, though not exactly happy, any improvements to the left were appreciated and valued. At least they made the first step.&lt;/p&gt;













&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;useful.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Possible political spectrum in the Lautenberg Act case&#34;&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;useful.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Possible political spectrum in the Lautenberg Act case
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivations to collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the pattern of the cosponsor, we need to understand their motivations. Lawmakers typically have three roles: legislation, oversight, and representation (Akirav, 2017). According to Schlesinger’s ambition theory, progressive legislators aim to win the re-election and obtain office from the party or committees. They are rational in deciding what political behaviors work best for them (Akirav, 2017). When it comes to cosponsor, they might evaluate whether this cooperation could fulfill their re-election ambitions or other career goals. For instance, lawmakers tend to adapt their decisions to public opinions and appeal to broader constituencies. Besides, following their party can build up reputations and earn trust from the party leaders. In this case, if they saw their votes’ great attention on the public health issues, or their party leader already announced their endorsement, these legislators were more likely to take part in the cosponsor program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rippere’s study separated the House and the Senate. The different systems result in differential performance and rationale for their members (Rippere, 2016). The term of each Representative is only two years. Their main goal is to win the re-election in a short time. Relatively, there is no time or incentive for them to connect with people with different party affiliations. Therefore, Representatives usually follow their party instead of communicating across the aisle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, Senators have six years to know only 100 members. Bipartisan collaboration is necessary and inevitable under many senate situations. For example, Senators can only realize their goals by preventing filibuster with two-third votes or obtaining unanimous consent. As a result, most senators have established cosponsor networks with equal numbers of colleagues from both parties (Rippere, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this particular case, Rippere found that two key supporters, Vitter and Inhofe, and eight cosponsors were all Gingrich senators. They are Republicans who used to work with Newt Gingrich then move up to the Senate. Gingrich senators brought the polarized partisanship from the House to the Senate (Ezra Klein, 2015). Even the most stubborn and conservative Republicans engaged in cosponsor, meaning that it is necessary and common for Senators to work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though TSCA Reform provided a perfect example of how the wonderful bipartisan cooperation could accomplish, the reform may not be the guaranteed success model for future legislation (Anthony Adragna, 2016). Many aspects play roles in promoting or preventing bills into law. Key factors include the interests of pivotal stakeholders, the current political landscape, the status quo position versus the Gridlock interval, and legislators’ preference of cooperation. Exploring bipartisan collaboration requires tremendous time, effort, and patience. As the Sen. Tom Udall said, “When people see what’s happened, they’ll say-like others have - that this is pretty close to a miracle in this environment.” Let’s hail the special and hard-won bipartisan achievement on environmental issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akirav, O. (2017). Legislators’ Patterns of Cooperation. International Journal of Social Science Studies, 5(2), 30–42.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony Adragna. (2016). Unlikely Alliances, Unending Tenacity Drove Chemical Safety Reform Over the Finish Line. U.S. Chemical Regulation Overhaul: TSCA Reform, 3–6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cory Gerlach. (2016, October 25). New Toxic Substances Control Act: An End to the Wild West for Chemical Safety? Science in the News. &lt;a href=&#34;http://sitn.hms.harvard.edu/flash/2016/new-toxic-substances-control-act-end-wild-west-chemical-safety/&#34;&gt;http://sitn.hms.harvard.edu/flash/2016/new-toxic-substances-control-act-end-wild-west-chemical-safety/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Vitter, former Senator for Louisiana. (2020). GovTrack.Us. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/members/david_vitter/400418&#34;&gt;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/members/david_vitter/400418&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dina Cappiello. (2015, January 21). Senate says climate change real, but doesn’t agree on cause. Phys. &lt;a href=&#34;https://phys.org/news/2015-01-senate-climate-real-doesnt.html&#34;&gt;https://phys.org/news/2015-01-senate-climate-real-doesnt.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eilperin, J., &amp;amp; Fears, D. (2016, May 19). Congress is overhauling an outdated law that affects nearly every product you own. Washington Post. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/congress-poised-to-pass-sweeping-reform-of-chemical-law/2016/05/18/0da5cd22-1d30-11e6-9c81-4be1c14fb8c8_story.html&#34;&gt;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/congress-poised-to-pass-sweeping-reform-of-chemical-law/2016/05/18/0da5cd22-1d30-11e6-9c81-4be1c14fb8c8_story.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental Defense Fund. (2020). Legislative history of chemicals policy reform. Environmental Defense Fund. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edf.org/health/legislative-history-chemicals-policy-reform&#34;&gt;https://www.edf.org/health/legislative-history-chemicals-policy-reform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental Protection. (2010, July 23). Rush and Waxman Release Toxic Chemicals Safety Act. Environmental Protection. &lt;a href=&#34;https://eponline.com/articles/2010/07/23/rush-and-waxman-release-toxic-chemicals-safety-act.aspx&#34;&gt;https://eponline.com/articles/2010/07/23/rush-and-waxman-release-toxic-chemicals-safety-act.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezra Klein. (2015). The Gingrich Senators and the U.S. Senate. TEXAS Liberal Arts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/government/news/feature-archive/the-gingrich-senators-and-the-u.s.-senate.php&#34;&gt;https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/government/news/feature-archive/the-gingrich-senators-and-the-u.s.-senate.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Vote Results for Roll Call 238. (2016, May 24). &lt;a href=&#34;http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2016/roll238.xml&#34;&gt;http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2016/roll238.xml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank Lautenberg. (2013). Ballotpedia. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ballotpedia.org/Frank_Lautenberg&#34;&gt;https://ballotpedia.org/Frank_Lautenberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank Lautenberg, former Senator for New Jersey. (2013). GovTrack.Us. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/members/frank_lautenberg/300064&#34;&gt;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/members/frank_lautenberg/300064&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kimberly Dean. (2015, May 14). Bipartisan Action on Lautenberg TSCA Reform Bill | Bipartisan Policy Center. Bipartisan Policy Center. &lt;a href=&#34;https://bipartisanpolicy.org/blog/bipartisan-action-taken-on-lautenberg-tsca-reform-bill/&#34;&gt;https://bipartisanpolicy.org/blog/bipartisan-action-taken-on-lautenberg-tsca-reform-bill/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plautz, J. (2013, May 23). CHEMICALS: How Lautenberg and Vitter found common ground on TSCA reform. E&amp;amp;E News. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eenews.net/stories/1059981681&#34;&gt;https://www.eenews.net/stories/1059981681&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Denison. (2016a, May 23). Historic deal on TSCA reform reached, setting stage for a new law after 40 years of waiting. EDF Health. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.edf.org/health/2016/05/23/historic-deal-on-tsca-reform-reached-setting-stage-for-a-new-law-after-40-years-of-waiting/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.edf.org/health/2016/05/23/historic-deal-on-tsca-reform-reached-setting-stage-for-a-new-law-after-40-years-of-waiting/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Denison. (2016b, June 10). Why passage of the Lautenberg Act is a really big deal. EDF Health. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.edf.org/health/2016/06/10/why-passage-of-the-lautenberg-act-is-a-really-big-deal/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.edf.org/health/2016/06/10/why-passage-of-the-lautenberg-act-is-a-really-big-deal/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rippere, P. S. (2016). Polarization Reconsidered: Bipartisan Cooperation through Bill Cosponsorship. Polity, 48(2), 243–278. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1057/pol.2016.4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1057/pol.2016.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheppard, K. (2015, March 18). Senate Seems Poised To Advance “Compromise” Chemical Regulation Bill. HuffPost. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/senate-chemical-hearing_n_6897404&#34;&gt;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/senate-chemical-hearing_n_6897404&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Udall, Markey, Durbin Announce Agreement on Chemical Safety Reform Bill. (2015, October 2). U.S. Senator Tom Udall of New Mexico. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tomudall.senate.gov/news/press-releases/udall-markey-durbin-announce-agreement-on-chemical-safety-reform-bill&#34;&gt;https://www.tomudall.senate.gov/news/press-releases/udall-markey-durbin-announce-agreement-on-chemical-safety-reform-bill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vogel, S. A., &amp;amp; Roberts, J. A. (2011). Why The Toxic Substances Control Act Needs An Overhaul, And How To Strengthen Oversight Of Chemicals In The Interim. Health Affairs, 30(5), 898–905. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1377/hlthaff.2011.0211&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1377/hlthaff.2011.0211&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice on expanding business via budgeting analysis</title>
      <link>/post/goat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/goat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmer Jaden McCoy wants to identify the feasibility of expanding his goat rental business by upgrading his truck and trailer into larger ones. We estimated the revenues and costs in options, whether buying new vehicles or not over the next five years. After comparing the internal rate of return with the discount rate, we recommend McCoy to purchase new transportation but accept jobs with longer periods in exchange for higher profits in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmer McCoy is interested in expanding his goat rental business but wants to ensure that he is maximizing profits from his business. Therefore, Farmer McCoy must decide whether or not it would be more profitable to purchase a larger truck and trailer and expand to a 32-goat operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local Soddy-Daisy, Tennessee goat farmer, Jaden McCoy, recently began renting his goats out for land clearing projects with initial success. Located in the foothills of the Smoky Mountains, Soddy-Daisy is plagued by harmful weeds, including kudzu. Goats have proven to be an efficient method for removing weeds from tough terrains, making McCoy’s goat rental business valuable. Obtaining a larger truck and trailer would allow for a larger goat operation and potentially lead to higher profits for farmer McCoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a. Define goals and options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To expand his business and capture profits in the five years, McCoy has two choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Option 1:&lt;/em&gt; Not purchasing any new equipment and maintaining the current business model of renting out 25 goats at a time. This option will not capture any value from the resale of his current truck and trailer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Option 2:&lt;/em&gt; Purchasing a bigger truck and trailer with a 32-goat capacity. This option will capture value through the sales of both old and new transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b. Articulate key assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to recognize the assumptions we made in this analysis because any change could alter our recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we assumed that there is an unlimited need for land clearing in Soddy-Daisy. So the number of available jobs won’t be a restrictive factor in farmer McCoy’s decision. While farmer McCoy’s current shepherd is only willing to work 50 five-day weeks per year and the goats must be tended by a shepherd during the jobs, the shepherd and goats can work a maximum of 250 days per year. Since 25 goats can finish one one-acre job in seven days, assuming they would keep the clearing rate, the same group of goats could complete 35 full jobs per year without the shepherd working overtime. Here we assumed that farmer McCoy would only schedule his goats to work one job per day and within each year, he would only accept jobs that would be completed. Each goat will be rented at $15 per day, regardless of whether or not they worked the entire day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, expanding to a 32-goat operation would increase efficiency by approximately 30%. It would take a team of 32 goats about 5.5 days to complete one job. Since we assume that farmer McCoy will only perform one job each day and half-days are charged at the same rental rate for whole days, he should allot six full days for his 32 goats to finish each job. At this rate, 32 goats will be able to accomplish 41 full jobs within a year, under the same clearing rate in option 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assumptions about additional costs include that, on average, each job will require $100 in setup costs building Trough, covered area, and mineral lick; 962 feet of fence sold at $0.75 per foot. Each workday will transport 80 round-trip miles with a cost of $0.63 per mile for the old truck, and $1.25 per mile for the new truck. Besides, we assumed that his old truck and trailer have an immediate resale value of $500 while obtaining a new truck and trailer would set him back $22,250 plus a 10% tax. The new transportation will also earn a resale value of $2,500 in the fifth year. We used an estimate of a 12% discount rate in present value calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. Forecast revenues, costs, and operating income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We considered McCoy’s net income, present value, and internal rate of return in budgets to compare the profitability of investing in a new truck and trailer or not. The efficiency differences between options 1 and 2 will affect the net income in each operation.  McCoy’s revenue comes from payment for his goat rental and resales his transportation. His fixed costs result from acquiring larger transportations with tax. Variable costs include shepherd wages, fence, and setup costs. After determining the net incomes (total revenue - total costs) over five years, we calculated the present value to find how much the future money is worth in today’s dollars. The net present values were then compared between options 1 and 2. Additionally, we evaluated the internal rate of return (IRR) to determine if investing in option 2 would be more profitable than not. An IRR greater than the discount rate of 12% signifies that option 2 would be the more profitable option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d. Financial and scenarios analyses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, option 2 has higher profitability than option 1 in five years. In option 2,  the yearly net income was greater than option 1. Though McCoy incurs higher total costs in year 0, he would then maintain higher revenues in the following years. Additionally, when comparing option 2 to option 1, the IRR (26%) is greater than the assumed discount rate (12%). This suggests that there is greater profit potential in option 2 than 1 if McCoy’s 32-goat team could complete 41 jobs per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we will have different results if we did not round to the nearest whole number during the days per job and jobs per year calculations. When assuming that a 32-goat team needs, on average, 5.47 days to complete one job, we find that this team is able to complete 45.71 jobs per year. Here, the IRR is lower, at roughly 9%, making option 2 (investing in the new truck and trailer) an unfavorable decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommendation&#34;&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our budget analysis, farmer McCoy should invest in the larger truck and trailer because it will be more profitable than his current business model under our assumptions. But McCoy should prioritize accepting jobs that require no less than six workdays to decrease costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, McCoy could explore other possibilities to increase profitability. He could reduce the variable cost of fencing by convincing his supplier to sell him less expensive fences in bulk. McCoy could also seek the potential to work for the government. A local government contract would ensure steady employment and consistent revenue each year and thus lower the costs from advertising and setup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Product Line Advice for Dove</title>
      <link>/post/dove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/dove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove should launch a new set of eco-friendly body care products to the market. The price premium will eventually cover the costs of organic and recycled certification and new product design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better fit in the highly intensive competitive market, follow the sustainability trends, and enhance Dove’s reputation in corporate social responsibility, I recommend Dove to introduce a new eco-friendly product series in body care and baby care. Commodities will adopt organic oat milk as one of the main ingredients with recycled paper packaging in milk carton shape. Customers may be willing to pay more for innovative and environmental friendly goods. Still, it will require time and money to earn necessary certificates and modify normal boxes into shower-friendly containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of Unilever, Dove, a personal care brand, established in 1957 only with a beauty bar (&amp;ldquo;Dove&amp;rdquo;). Now Dove expands as an international brand, owning factories in 21 countries, with products sold to over 80 countries (Bhasin &amp;amp; Nesselrode 2018). Dove’s marketing channels are diverse: retail stores, discount stores, supermarkets, and online (Bhasin &amp;amp; Dexter 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004, Dove initiated Real Beauty campaigns involving building confidence and self-esteem for women, which went viral at that time (&amp;ldquo;Dove&amp;rdquo;). Target customers of Dove are middle or middle-upper-class people. Most of them are women between 15-50 years old who care about their appearance and would like to spend money on healthier products with less harmful chemicals (Bhasin &amp;amp; Nesselrode 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers today have a high tendency for sustainable and organic products. According to the statistics report from SimilarWeb, 85.05% of people get to dove.com by searching with the leading keyword “Organic” in 2019 (&amp;ldquo;dove.com Traffic Statistics&amp;rdquo; 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to Unilever’s pledge on less plastic, Dove plans to use zero plastic on beauty bars globally before 2020, switch all plastic packaging into 100% recycled ones before 2025, and have created a new technology to reduce plastic in deodorant (&amp;ldquo;Dove moves to 100% recycled plastic bottles&amp;rdquo; 2019). Dove also obtained the accreditation from People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA), presenting their products are cruelty-free without any experiment on animals (&amp;ldquo;Dove Goes Cruelty-Free&amp;rdquo; 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’Oréal, one of Unilever’s competitors, started a sustainable personal care brand Seed Phytonutrients in 2017. The brand featured in botanical ingredients and paper-based packaging (L’Oréal Group). Compared to similar brands, Seed captured a considerable price premium. For example, an 8.5 fluid ounce shampoo can be sold at $24 in Seed, but at $7.99 in L’Oreal Paris on their websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a.Market segment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.Vegans;
ii. Green advocates;
iii. Parents who carefully choose products for their children;
iv. Young people who like to try novel and well-designed products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b. Willingness to pay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most customers of Dove are not price-sensitive, meaning that they would pay for the price premium in exchange for organic and eco-friendly products. Dove fans, recognizing Dove’s impact on changing social perception, may support the new campaign about the environment as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Vegan people who enjoy the oat milk may also be interested in these products. Plus, the cruelty-free products can show their value and concept as nature protectors. Environmental enthusiasts may find paper packaging performing better in creating less plastic waste than recycled plastic bottles. The organic food level experience will bring another winning point. Combining with baby care products, oat milk offers parents an impression of moisture and mild nourishment. The organic certificate seems healthier and more trustworthy than Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson who are often under suspicion with hormone issues in their baby products (CBS News 2012). The unique food-like design of the products will also catch people’s eyes on them immediately. They may imagine when applying the products, their bodies will feel like drinking oat milk too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove needs certifications from non-government organizations to convince consumers that its green products are guaranteed. One of the famous NGOs, The Forest Stewardship Council (FSC), is most familiar and trusted by Customers. To secure the FSC recycled label, Dove must verify all wood in the products come from 100% reused material (&amp;ldquo;FSC Labels&amp;rdquo;). In the production process, every section is under a strict custody chain from certificate Conformity Assessments Bodies (CABs) (&amp;ldquo;Assurance Services International&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) certificates organic body care products as the same rigid regulation as organic food. Products with less than 70% organic ingredients cannot use the term “organic” (&amp;ldquo;Cosmetics&amp;rdquo; 2008). Dove also has to pay less than $750 to USDA for the organic certification cost-share program (&amp;ldquo;Organic Certification Cost Share Programs&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, it is not sufficient to take the milk cartons as body care packaging — the new generation of pack demands robust and anti-water technologies and designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up, huge costs will lie in organic raw materials, schemes for recycled containers, and all honest, responsible production resulting from these certifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommendation&#34;&gt;Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dove can also approach popular brands for organic oat milk like Oatly. The cooperation between two different areas will draw much attention and increase profits. When customers choose a body wash, they may discover the organic product associated with their familiar food brands. Other consumers might fall in love with the smell after trying the wash and become potential customers for oak milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove.” Unilever USA, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unileverusa.com/brands/personal-care/dove.html&#34;&gt;https://www.unileverusa.com/brands/personal-care/dove.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhasin, Hitesh, and Graham Nesselrode. “Marketing Strategy of Dove - Dove Marketing Strategy.” Marketing91, 16 June 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-strategy-of-dove/&#34;&gt;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-strategy-of-dove/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhasin, Hitesh, and Dexter. “Marketing Mix of Dove - Dove Marketing Mix and 4 Ps.” Marketing91, 20 May 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-mix-dove/&#34;&gt;https://www.marketing91.com/marketing-mix-dove/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove.com Traffic Statistics.” SimilarWeb, 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.similarweb.com/website/dove.com#search&#34;&gt;https://www.similarweb.com/website/dove.com#search&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove Moves to 100% Recycled Plastic Bottles.” Unilever Global Company Website, Oct. 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unilever.com/news/news-and-features/Feature-article/2019/dove-moves-to-100-per-cent-recycled-plastic-bottles.html&#34;&gt;https://www.unilever.com/news/news-and-features/Feature-article/2019/dove-moves-to-100-per-cent-recycled-plastic-bottles.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dove Goes Cruelty-Free.” PETA, 9 Oct. 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.peta.org/about-peta/victories/dove-goes-cruelty-free/&#34;&gt;https://www.peta.org/about-peta/victories/dove-goes-cruelty-free/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’Oréal Group. “Seed Phytonutrients - L&#39;Oréal Group: World Leader in Beauty: Official Website.” L&#39;Oréal - L&#39;Oréal Group, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.loreal.com/brand/professional-products-division/seed-phytonutrients&#34;&gt;https://www.loreal.com/brand/professional-products-division/seed-phytonutrients&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBS News. “Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson to Phase out Potentially Harmful Chemicals by 2015.” CBS News, CBS Interactive, 15 Aug. 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/johnson-johnson-to-phase-out-potentially-harmful-chemicals-by-2015/&#34;&gt;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/johnson-johnson-to-phase-out-potentially-harmful-chemicals-by-2015/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“FSC Labels: Forest Stewardship Council.” FSC Labels | Forest Stewardship Council, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fsc.org/en/page/fsc-labels&#34;&gt;https://fsc.org/en/page/fsc-labels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Assurance Services International.” ASI, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asi-assurance.org/s/find-a-cab&#34;&gt;http://www.asi-assurance.org/s/find-a-cab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Organic Certification Cost Share Programs.” Organic Certification Cost Share Programs | Agricultural Marketing Service, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ams.usda.gov/services/grants/occsp&#34;&gt;https://www.ams.usda.gov/services/grants/occsp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmetics, Body Care Products, and Personal Care Product. Apr. 2008, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/OrganicCosmeticsFactSheet.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/OrganicCosmeticsFactSheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
